<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Information Security on rdner's blog</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/</link><description>Recent content in Information Security on rdner's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Paranoid Habits. Privacy Tips</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/privacy-tips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 12:01:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/privacy-tips/</guid><description>Recently I gave a talk to my colleagues where I shared some information about the modern state of data collection and privacy violation. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to avoid all of the tracking but one can take some steps to minimize the amount of collected data.
Why Care about Privacy? Surprisingly, when I raise privacy questions I often get something like:
Why should I care? I have nothing to hide, I obey the law.</description></item><item><title>My automated backups to AWS S3 with client-side AES256</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/s3-aes256-backups/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/s3-aes256-backups/</guid><description>What I was looking for. Requirements The reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t just start using some backup software with built-in encryption is a pure lack of trust. So, if you&amp;rsquo;re fine with someone managing your backups, you might think the approach described here is a total overkill. And it&amp;rsquo;s okay. But there are some people out there who have the same trust issues that I do and they might find this article useful, so I write it for them.</description></item><item><title>Paranoid Habits. Security Tips</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/security-tips/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 12:01:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/security-tips/</guid><description>Recently I gave a talk to my colleagues where I shared some tools I use to secure my online presence and communication. Some of the listed things can be very technical but some of them I believe are crucial to know as a part of the daily life in the modern world.
Disclaimer I&amp;rsquo;m not a security expert, please check every word I write.
Although, I have some experience in basic pen-testing and I have exposed some vulnerabilities in the past, I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself an expert in this area.</description></item><item><title>How to secure your web apps (at least a little bit)</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/secure-web-apps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 10:05:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/secure-web-apps/</guid><description>Disclaimer I&amp;rsquo;m not a security expert, please check every word I write.
Although, I have some experience in basic pen-testing and I have exposed some vulnerabilities in the past, I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself an expert in this area. There are people out there whose full-time job is information security and I&amp;rsquo;m not going to pretend I&amp;rsquo;m one of them. I just do some CTFs as a hobby and build software as my daily job, so it gives me enough knowledge to write such articles and give such talks but does not make me an expert.</description></item></channel></rss>