<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music on rdner's blog</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/music/</link><description>Recent content in Music on rdner's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rdner.de/posts/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cyber City</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/music/cyber-city-single/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/music/cyber-city-single/</guid><description>This single was inspired by the Ghost in the Shell movie. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the anime and went to see the movie. Although I didn&amp;rsquo;t like how the story was changed, I appreciated the visuals and the original soundtrack.
Guitar: modified .strandberg* Boden OS7 Bass: Ibanez SR305EB-WK Guitar FX: Axe FX II Cyber City</description></item><item><title>.strandberg* Boden OS7 — my perfect guitar</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/music/strandberg-boden-os-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/music/strandberg-boden-os-7/</guid><description>Hey, everyone! In my previous post I promised to write about the .strandberg* guitar I had ordered because it definitely deserved a separate post. Well, here we go! I’m going to share all my thoughts on .strandberg* Boden OS7, all the up/down sides I found and how I fixed what I didn’t like and eventually got a perfect guitar for myself.
A short disclaimer: this post is my personal opinion and nobody paid me for this.</description></item><item><title>Chasing a perfect guitar</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/music/chasing-perfect-guitar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/music/chasing-perfect-guitar/</guid><description>Disclaimer A guitar or its sound is a very subjective topic, I don’t claim that I know the best about guitars and any related gear, everything is written here is my personal opinion according to my preferences and experience (which I don’t have much, for sure).
How it started Can’t remember exactly, when my parents bought me my first guitar but I have this picture from May 20th, 2005 where I play my first guitar ever.</description></item><item><title>Space</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/music/space-single/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/music/space-single/</guid><description>This single is my first ever finished work playing guitar.
Guitar: Gibson SG Standard Bass: Ibanez SR300EB-CA Guitar FX: Zoom G3 Space</description></item><item><title>Inside The Machine</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/music/inside-the-machine-album/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/music/inside-the-machine-album/</guid><description>This album is my first ever experiment with producing music. The idea was to express in music how one would feel inside a busy computer processing signals and working hard. The focus was definitely on the percussion.
Just to manage your expectations: I had never produced any electronic music before I worked on this. I didn&amp;rsquo;t try to match a certain genre or mimic someone, also most of the samples are taken from existing libraries.</description></item></channel></rss>