<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on rdner's blog</title><link>https://rdner.de/</link><description>Recent content in Home on rdner's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rdner.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why run?</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/sport/why-run/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/sport/why-run/</guid><description>Short Answer The short answer is:
It makes me happy, it makes me better
Not satisfied? Welcome to the long version&amp;hellip;
Long Answer I always hesitated to give a long answer in person. Mainly, because it required me to communicate so many things in a short amount of time and, most likely, I would not be able to find the best words to do so. Fortunately, smart people invented writing which allows us to be better at choosing the best words.</description></item><item><title>Paranoid Habits. Privacy Tips</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/privacy-tips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 12:01:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/privacy-tips/</guid><description>Recently I gave a talk to my colleagues where I shared some information about the modern state of data collection and privacy violation. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to avoid all of the tracking but one can take some steps to minimize the amount of collected data.
Why Care about Privacy? Surprisingly, when I raise privacy questions I often get something like:
Why should I care? I have nothing to hide, I obey the law.</description></item><item><title>Riding in Granada, Spain</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/motorcycle/granada-spain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/motorcycle/granada-spain/</guid><description>I like traveling. Bragging facts: at the moment I&amp;rsquo;ve visited 15 countries and 32 places, spent in total 102 days traveling. Since I got my motorbike license, I had 2 trips that went particularly well: Lanzarote and this one – Granada in Spain. What&amp;rsquo;s different? This time my wife and I rented a motorbike and went exploring. In fact, it went so well with Lanzarote that in Granada we even took a guided tour from a local company (details later) and started filming our trip on camera (only pictures before).</description></item><item><title>My automated backups to AWS S3 with client-side AES256</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/s3-aes256-backups/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/s3-aes256-backups/</guid><description>What I was looking for. Requirements The reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t just start using some backup software with built-in encryption is a pure lack of trust. So, if you&amp;rsquo;re fine with someone managing your backups, you might think the approach described here is a total overkill. And it&amp;rsquo;s okay. But there are some people out there who have the same trust issues that I do and they might find this article useful, so I write it for them.</description></item><item><title>Paranoid Habits. Security Tips</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/security-tips/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 12:01:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/security-tips/</guid><description>Recently I gave a talk to my colleagues where I shared some tools I use to secure my online presence and communication. Some of the listed things can be very technical but some of them I believe are crucial to know as a part of the daily life in the modern world.
Disclaimer I&amp;rsquo;m not a security expert, please check every word I write.
Although, I have some experience in basic pen-testing and I have exposed some vulnerabilities in the past, I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself an expert in this area.</description></item><item><title>How to secure your web apps (at least a little bit)</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/secure-web-apps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 10:05:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/security/secure-web-apps/</guid><description>Disclaimer I&amp;rsquo;m not a security expert, please check every word I write.
Although, I have some experience in basic pen-testing and I have exposed some vulnerabilities in the past, I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself an expert in this area. There are people out there whose full-time job is information security and I&amp;rsquo;m not going to pretend I&amp;rsquo;m one of them. I just do some CTFs as a hobby and build software as my daily job, so it gives me enough knowledge to write such articles and give such talks but does not make me an expert.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://rdner.de/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/about/</guid><description>Denis Rechkunov I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer based in Berlin, Germany.
My experience is quite diverse: it goes from binary protocols and communication with devices to back-end services and front-end apps. Although I worked on user interfaces in the past, I found my passion in building complex distributed systems.
When I&amp;rsquo;m not an engineer I am 🏊‍♂️🚴‍♂️🏃‍♂️, 🏍, 🎸, 📷
When sending sensitive data to me, please, use this public key.</description></item><item><title>Riding on Lanzarote, Spain</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/motorcycle/lanzarote/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/motorcycle/lanzarote/</guid><description>This is the first time we went somewhere after I got my motorbike license, so &amp;ldquo;why not rent a bike and explore the whole island by riding together&amp;rdquo; we thought. Now, looking back, I&amp;rsquo;d say it was a bit sketchy because I had not have enough experience riding in mountains before but, in the end, it went well, I was very careful and didn&amp;rsquo;t try to ride above my abilities.</description></item><item><title>Cyber City</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/music/cyber-city-single/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/music/cyber-city-single/</guid><description>
This single was inspired by the Ghost in the Shell movie. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the anime and went to see the movie. Although I didn&amp;rsquo;t like how the story was changed, I appreciated the visuals and the original soundtrack.
Guitar: modified .strandberg* Boden OS7 Bass: Ibanez SR305EB-WK Guitar FX: Axe FX II Cyber City</description></item><item><title>.strandberg* Boden OS7 — my perfect guitar</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/music/strandberg-boden-os-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/music/strandberg-boden-os-7/</guid><description>Hey, everyone! In my previous post I promised to write about the .strandberg* guitar I had ordered because it definitely deserved a separate post. Well, here we go! I’m going to share all my thoughts on .strandberg* Boden OS7, all the up/down sides I found and how I fixed what I didn’t like and eventually got a perfect guitar for myself.
A short disclaimer: this post is my personal opinion and nobody paid me for this.</description></item><item><title>Chasing a perfect guitar</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/music/chasing-perfect-guitar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/music/chasing-perfect-guitar/</guid><description>Disclaimer A guitar or its sound is a very subjective topic, I don’t claim that I know the best about guitars and any related gear, everything is written here is my personal opinion according to my preferences and experience (which I don’t have much, for sure).
How it started Can’t remember exactly, when my parents bought me my first guitar but I have this picture from May 20th, 2005 where I play my first guitar ever.</description></item><item><title>Space</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/music/space-single/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/music/space-single/</guid><description>
This single is my first ever finished work playing guitar.
Guitar: Gibson SG Standard Bass: Ibanez SR300EB-CA Guitar FX: Zoom G3 Space</description></item><item><title>People don’t remember what the word “engineer” means anymore and I think they should.</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/engineer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/tech/engineer/</guid><description>What “engineer” means to me? When I was studying at Altay State Technical University in the small town Barnaul in Russia we used to think about ourselves as engineers not just developers.
The educational system in Russia was very different in comparison with the western system at that point. We didn’t have Bachelor’s or Master’s degree we had a qualification level and in my case it was “Engineer in software development and automated systems”.</description></item><item><title>Inside The Machine</title><link>https://rdner.de/posts/music/inside-the-machine-album/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rdner.de/posts/music/inside-the-machine-album/</guid><description>This album is my first ever experiment with producing music. The idea was to express in music how one would feel inside a busy computer processing signals and working hard. The focus was definitely on the percussion.
Just to manage your expectations: I had never produced any electronic music before I worked on this. I didn&amp;rsquo;t try to match a certain genre or mimic someone, also most of the samples are taken from existing libraries.</description></item></channel></rss>